Geoff Walker

Web Developer



Contact















Skills

- HTML
- CSS
- Tavascript
 - SASS
 - SOL
- ISON Data
- API Calls

Overview

As a professional mechanical engineer, I have years of experience designing and developing new products. However, after a nasty fall left me an amputee, my career as an engineer ended abruptly, little did I know my true calling for programming had only just begun. This shouldn't have come as a surprise to me, having developed many databases and applications over the years, including a fully featured Customer Relations Manager (CRM), along with the two years I spent in data for the local council.

Since early 2021, I have been teaching myself front-end code, to accompany, the more familiar to me, back end code. I have also been using the time to develop my programming skills and work as a freelance developer. I am now looking for a full-time role as web developer, where I can further develop my software skills and can look to get back on my proverbial if not physical feet.

Projects

Aspects of Beauty

- Website
- Designed and built client website
- Developed to be fully responsive

Time Tracking App

- Website App
- Developed App
- Used ISON data to propergate

Rock Paper Scissors

Webgame

- Designed and built game design
- Developed game logic

Calculator

Application

- Designed and built calculator app
- Developed calculator logic

Forkify App

Application

- Developed App using MVC methodology
- Obtained data using API

Nexter Website

Website

- Developed site using SASS variables
- Made fully responsive

Work Experience

Freelance Web Developer Geoff-Walker.io

- 🖈 Remote 📰 Jun 2021 – Current
- Building fully responsive customer websites
- Coding Javascript applications
- Designing volunteer management software
- Extending current competancies

Performance Officer **Lincolnshire County Council**

- Lincoln
- Apr 2015 Feb 2017
- Managing Schools and Child Protection Databases
- Database maintenance in SQL
- Business intelligence, form creation
- Completing freedom of information requests

Spares and Components Sales Engineer Zeppelin Systems Ltd

- Nottinghamshire
- Managed Spares Department
- Wrote full CRM system to replace paper note system
- First line of technical support
- Selling proactive and reactive spares

Foodbank Project Manager **Acts Trust**

- 3 Oct 2009 Dec 2010 - Managed project delivery
- Sourced funding and food donations - Maintained the Foodbank database

Applications Engineer

- Zeppelin Systems Ltd Sept 2008 - Aug 2009 Nottinghamshire **
- Designed customer systems
- Wrote articles for publication
- Technical sales support - Created 50 page sales brochure

Engineering Manager Materials Handling Products

- *Swadlincote sep 2007 – Apr 2008
- Managed Spares Department
- Wrote full CRM system to replace paper note system
- First line of technical support
- Selling proactive and reactive spares

Design Engineer NMB-Minebea UK Ltd

- Lincoln
- Mag 2006 Aug 2007
- Designed Aerospace components with Solidworks
- Mathematically modelling design proofs
- Developing new materials
- Shop floor troubleshooting

Science Teacher Huntcliff School

- Kirton Lindsev
- May 2000 Sep 2003
- Taught Science across age and ability ranges
- Pastoral care for form group Yr7-8
- Excellent exam results

Production Engineer James Dawson & Son

- 📆 May 2000 Sep 2003 - Implementing ERP software system
- Developing databases and applications
- New product and material development
- Shop floor troubleshooting

Supervisor Halfords

Retford

Sep 1999 - Apr 2000

- Retail management

Education

- Postgraduate Diploma Materials Science Loughborough University, Graduated 2008
- Postgraduate Certificate in Education (PGCE) Secondary Science Teaching Bishop Grosseteste University, Graduated 2004
- Higher National Certificate (HNC) Mechanical Engineering Lincoln College, Graduated 2002